All right good afternoon everyone thanks for joining the...of the day.
So, man is going to be hard to compute those
...limos demos bob I do have some cool demos today thanks for staying late.
So, they were going to focus on excel powerpoint
and word audience we're going to drill down a little bit more into the development experience for the
...for people that are in familiar with them already.
My name is rolando human anomaly program manager on the whole physics
and civility platform team I've been working with office
...for six years now I've been witness of the evolution of
the different extensibility model so it's great to see how we're moving
towards a new model where you can use web technologies to extend office in are very...way.
Please...forget to do the...that slide so,
the agenda for today iswe're going to do a quick overview of office audience.
I'm going to spend most of the
...talking about what's new what is the new developments that we have made in the last three
to six months since the last big conference...to talk a little bit about the
role bob what's coming in the future and then
when aspirin some time talking about the call-to-action so in terms of
...how the session fits in the overall framing of for the rest of the developer
talks...going to focusing decision about bringing
...new user experiences into office so the left-hand side of
...is what this session is all about?
So, let's value in.
So, you probably so these...about the opportunity to
...office there's obviously some impressive numbers over there one more than
one billion users using office for an average of two hours
every day so that's a big opportunity there's a captive market there ...
decreed solutions that extend office you-can reach to all these big audience so for
...going to focus on the aspect the number of users
and the time they spend inside the office publications because obvious audiences precisely to bring
your custom experiences inside the applications that...use the most.
And, from my perspective this is all about productivity so.
Why would you
extend office as opposed to just create your own web application
...mobile application where I think we need to think about to perspectives one is the
end-user perspective which is we want to...users more productive offices approach
to really sweet it's already helping users to be productive well-versed field a lot of
opportunities or... customers scenarios where users have a lot of
the information under data in excel but they often in a big enterprise
...to...systems sites you...constantly switching to
...screens to connect to customer data copy
the data put it into excel deformities not correct spend twenty minutes just
formatting the data and it's a lot of lots of protein...so even though they are...one of the
...productivity suites in the planet they still have
these inefficiencies so productivity
for end-users can be optimized by creating these custom solutions
ringing the connectivity the collaboration linear in the context of office?
Now from a developer perspective developing of is also makes a lot of sense
so-so developer if you are going to
...solution that has functions where office already
...like collaboration content
...data analysis...start from scratch why invents
...way to do things if all
...is users already familiar with...way of is also you can build on top of office
...and then save a lot of time and...
your users offer users are much valuable experience
enough familiar product that they already use two hours in average of a.
So, without context.
There's one talk a little bit about the
new web audience so you probably heard the rename from apps for
...to the new office audience.
this is something that we are doing to reflect on the history that we have had
...office extensibility we have hub commodities...audience and people
were a little bit confuse with the notion of apps and the fact that you have mobile
...web apps and abs inside office
apps so we decided to go with
audience which sounds goodpeople understand it so, it's a...of
...so I'd like to ask of these point how
many of you I already familiar with apps for office or have developed enough...
...so, throughout this session ...office are going to be office audience
in the problems your will still see the
...roughest there is going to take some time for us to propagate
the name but eventually everything will be called audience in all the products so,
you see in some the screen shots or even the pros
...terrifies those are what we called office audience and when whenever
we need to distinguish we're going to use the web audience to make sure we're talking about the new type of audience
now let me ask you how many of you have created or have solutions in the
...or via seo technology so quite a bit so
you're pretty familiar with how to extend office so I probably don't need to
...you more about the value of doing these?
So, let me just
...right into...some...most I want to show you the current state.
Of office...
So, you've seen the we have a store a lot of developers have already
published thousands of different apps in the store.
In these last few years we've seen a lot of very interesting apps coming up
...that allow you to really enhancer productivity so when I show you just a few
of the abs that are already there just to give you a sense of what's happening in the market
...I start with these business solutions apps in xcel.
Which is created by...reproduce one of the companies that has one of the
largest database in the world about business they have information
about revenue contact information marketing information and they create
the solution excel that allows me to pull information from their database
...excels I can manipulated their in this case let's...
small software company and I want to sell my problem for small retailers here in the
area...I would like to find some prospects so I'm going to use these solution from
...they have these marketing solutions
where they offer media ability to request a prospect least...
and some criteria so I'm going to click on that the first thing I'm going to do is
enter the concrete so let's...
American-type.
And, actually...what's around here.
So,...because I'm going to select these area and then
my target market these small retail companies I want to help them be more productive but
how more sales so.
What type of retail there and get the actual filter I want
in this case I want to all the retail stores in the area and I want to focus on companies that
have a lot of employees and are not doing that well with revenue so let's
say I want less than a million dollars in revenue
but they have more than ten employees so let's see how
...comes up...going to say load
they're going to the charter transactions against you see some very interesting
...models happening already in the market I'm going to accept
the charge?
They go fetch the data from the database...is ready for me to insert
...click here...boom I have the data in excel now since I'm in
Already can start doing some of the things that I would naturally doing excel like, for example,
do some conditional formatting for some of these data to see
where'd employees are but I want to...a little bit more than that I'm going to use
a capabilities and the fact that I'm already in excel?
Create...for me in this case I want to get
...address for these businesses because I want to see
them up so but the data came in different columns so what I'm going to say is
use the excel data feel functionality to help me get the full address
...one single field in this case I'm just going to
put an example I'm going to copy the address of the first one.
And, this is...and.
...cure-all.
...copied...to show excel what I
want from these three columns I'm going to do the data tab...a flash field
so excel is going to automatically give me...
...addresses once we have that now I can select
that entire set of companies and I want to use another up in this case
...maps up which you probably are very familiar with and just tell being maps
a please give-me a map of those addresses the just...I'm going to use this
other visualization which actually allows me to better
drill down and see which companies have a lot of
employees but not a lot of sales in this case I can see these red circles
...the ratio between employee and sales is bigger legacy these guys have
nineteen employees and not even a million sales were us these guys have a million sales
...thirteen employees so these guys probably need help I can go so my product
to them so this is a great way to bring
...idea have to leave excel to achieve these call...scenario.
Now you've been hearing a lot...bcs
a platform for all of office all of the client so...just...to demonstrate
how this room going to save these into my one drive I'm going to grow libm?
And, then I'm going to go to my one grieve on the web.
...let's do one grieve.
Motion see...new prospects...group here.
now if I click where I would expect that I will get the exact same experience I left on the
desktop so this ability to move from one device to an order and continue
to be provocative I get my map here...can continue to drilled.
I can get more data with the business solutions up good another cheat and start editing
...so you can see the our of
these model now let me jump now into ward.
And, in...you're probably seeing a lot of the reference abs wikipedia
translation all those are very simple labs but thegive you good productivity
boosters in some cases I'm starting to see some very interesting ones like these mind
...that I found the other day this one is
really interesting because it allows me to very easily generate content.
Without having to do a lot of efforts in this case let's say I'm editing a document and I
want to do some brainstorming...one of the
terms of the key terms in my writing...this case I'm going to select
award in this case video I'm going to say.
Give me insights about...grid newm mind map for video and
these of is going to search the web and give-me terms related to...
Particular word in this case I
see there is technology one I want to drill down a little bit more and see what's in the
web about technology I can say map node and then these will continue to search the web and
give-me more insights...I can create my own ideas.
And, once I'm gone I can of course come here and say one
to these diagram
to my documents boom I have creative very quickly we
have living work a whole new type of diagram without having to install
...application goal switch convex etc.
And, then lastly just to our wrap-up with powerpoint you probably seen all those
...codes that we have...this lies world there's some nab that allows you to
very easily do about in powerpoint we have these your code generator
I like these app especially in this type of scenario so, for example,
I want to...the cure called for the...dot office dot com which is the main
destination that we use and I want to make it bigger I want to make it
...too much this slide...once I'm done I can crappie.
And, pasted here and in a matter of seconds I already created mike your
code for my for my session similarly you probably seen ...the robs like
...everywhere which allows me to do live audience...inside my
presentations and we are we have also seen a lot of
enthusiasm in the education space so there is these very cool interactive
...the people are putting in presentations especially teachers that teach their students
aboutdifferent topics in this case look at these teachers in the about...
The concentration of a particular substance in the water I can play with these and I
can really learn about some science topic in this
case with these nice applications so.
Pretty cool people are starting to be creative and
enabled very interesting scenarios.
Bob people always ask me can you really create
a enterprise solutions with...platform means
...ready and even though you probably seen...there are some
api gaps we are working on filling those as fast as we can but
today we have already a lot of what you need to create real-world solutions.
And, I want to just show youthe architecture behind the sap them all
the you guys have seen I'm going to...to the in this session one more time
I know you have seen it twice when I show you one more time to make sure
the you understand what's going on behind the scenes in this case
...more is based on architecture like these there's ...
adding in office...ask read this enterprise gate where the resource on the cloud
that basically allows you to get access to...
Even your own premise
...from mississippi through these gateway...you need to do from your office out in
this connect to some piece of software in the cloud that is the door
into your enterprise data so it is possibleto...and
...data and systems that are home frame in this case the other
challenging aspect is also the identity cover you manage identity's so
what we're doing is they're mapping the...sixty-five entities to the
sap identity so there's some configuration...initial setup that happens
...ones that it's done you can securely login from your obviously sixty-five
tenant into their service and then into a cp so.
Let me just quickly show you how that works?
Close.
These one here.
...ok so here's the
...the mobile you've seen a couple of times already so what I
...to make sure this is not just smoke and...the sap client
...my machine that is connecting to a realistically system hosted on the cloud
and, I'll show you what that looks like.
...going to open.
Going to be brave here I definitely felt like a fish out of the water in these
But, I'm going to try so I'm going to login on my sap system.
I need to remember the name of the table that I need to connects bob.
Going through all those hurdles now this is the screens the...users see
every day or...data so here I have a collection of records
in this case you can see is the same data set that I'm showing in
excel and I'm already connected so what I want to show you is how the objects are happening
real-time so I'm going to come here you can cvs particular the first
...the contact name is some.
Some other person so I'm going to say I'm going I'm going to be the contact for bowed car
...obviously these record use.
Rightnow looks like these in a cp here's the contact I just change
...let me take over like the first three cars I'm going
to be the promoter of those cards and these
in this project so when I say let's compare save as you have
seen so this is going to connect to the cpc system and,
check what changes have people made over what changes have made and
...I laws the connection we tried to reload.
Sometimes this happens.
Okay, so, that's two comparing save.
There we go so increments...via cpc system it recognizes that I have change three
...and it gives me the opportunity to review
goals so liquid changes in this case...I say I want to keep all the
excel changes of the cp so I'm dom now I can go back to my is
...and refresh here.
If I look at the record.
I should see my name is a contact over there so.
Berry real credible end-to-end solutions are really possible we've been
your platforms...all you need to do is your user existing web skills
and are connect to systems...already know-how to connect to the web...cloud?
...so...but it's possible to the
now let's look at what's new what have we be working on
in the last three to six months so I'm going to show you a serious of the most to
...these so the first one I'm going to start with the one
that were most proud of which is the work we've been doing on the.
Ipod and you probably seen a few them also
...when...quickly demonstrate again the multiplied
from aspect so I just created prospects a sheets.
Verbs in the desktop...I opened
...long online now if I come here because my account
disconnected to muh obviously sixty-five...a number
...you see how it already show showed up in my recent
documents I'm going to click prospects you would expect to see.
Exactly the same serving the...save on the desktop.
Now let's see if the network.
Google alright so there really is so,
you can see the same code base ...changes to the apps on the
apps are running on the...as well so this is...we're starting to
...really about promise of broad ones and
wrong all the different platforms and as you so we're going to start enabling many more
platforms in the future so
now let's jump into the developer experience so, what has changed there?
So,...the this opportunity to talk about some of the new experiences that we enable for
developers so for those of you that are not
familiar rand-r still learning...a new set of content
...make you makes it really easy to learn about office
outings so this is the new getting started page from out of the office
...com so you go there today this was release just these morning the you will
find that there's information about of...different five-eighty gis and also about
audience we released a new explore javascript.
Page which is very handy if you want to just go on
...some of the api are available you have basically
embedded excel on-line and you can try some code right there without doing anything more than
...browse to the page so, for example,
like in run this code here.
And, see what...it...to the spreadsheet
and there's more samples over there if I go back.
Close that I'm going to also show you now than we
have the accessible how the you test and develop considering the so
let's just create a very quick project and see how also developer you can put it on the so
that you can for your application make sure that everything's working because even volume...one
code base you still need to make sure that it works across all the different browser versions in the
case of ios you will be working with a safari so this is no different than the web you need to
...your web app multiple browsers is very similar here so it's always a good idea
of to the sign for responsiveness for all these different
...factors but also there's the different browsersto make sure the everything is working
fine so let's just create a very simple app put it on the from a developer
perspective so for that I'm going to use the newvisual studio
all online experience...some of you already saw these
...moines the session for the developer keynote working with outlook
...we also enabled the ability to use nap without requiring
and...sixty-five signing which was a lot of the feedback receive
...was too much of...requirement so we enable the use of map
...with your emissary account so you come here and get started you-can signing with
...your called mail account.
And, this will give you.
...up experience I'm going to create on your project and I'm
going to say I want to create the service realization.
Out in just create so nothing fancy there's
a crawled run it.
So, I have already are working app.
The release.
And, started it's a fully functional.
...your it allows you to visualize in this case
...sample data now I'm going to go back to map and,
show you how to moved out from...environment to the odb because I want
this the there so for that I'm going to using this case visual studio but you don't need
visual studio I'm just going to use visual studio for convenience in this case so,
map allows you to download the project to
...studio when...save the file.
And, open it...generates...file that is going to launch
...visual studio automatically with the same project that I just created.
So, I'm going to use visual studio.
To publish these easily to
...website so in order to logged these application on that but I want to
loaded from
...or to see that it's loading correctly from the right environment so what I'm going to
do here is an obviously if I if I run these on the desktop it...wrong.
Just to make sure I'm going to...the...so it's running here on the
desktop using visual studio and it's working world so
...going to stop that.
And, now what I'm going to do is going to polish these.
Rightly publish I'm going to create a new publishing profile
...it them all.
And, I'm going to...so I
want to show you some of the nice features of visual studio you already have a measure
...with your imis...or...account you can chrome directly to the profile
...in the publishing experience...and select I want
to published to one of my usher websites this is going to
recognize your account because I'm standing here I'm going to polish these
...to these website here.
And,...say publish.
So, that is going to put all the html
...javascript of the and measure websites so.
Once it's...it should launch a browser.
It's not...to the...but if I go to the art...directory of the
app which is home html it is there so the app is already
live in usher websites now the only thing I'm missing in order to see that in my
ad pog use a I need to side load the manifest of the...of the know
that app exes so that's what I'm going to do next so I'm going to
...back to visual studio on-again say publish
...package the app I'm going to make sure this is going to connect
...which is a requirement for all office audience and say
finish and this is going to give me the manifest here release this is the
...that I need to put on my...bob so that I can test that up
here so let's go ahead and do that now I'm going to have to disconnect my mouse to be able to plugging
...the way I do it is very easily already installed
...tones in my are windows pc but if you have a mark
this will be a major experience to?
Image of...here.
All I need to do is.
Open-eyed tombs.
And, I hope.
And, recognizes...
...wait for my bc to recognize the.
...for some reason it's not...
From to...directly.
So, now the I disconnect the so all I need to do is
strong to the app section.
...load and cv apps that are available there you can see
...have excel and word so I'm going...drop the
...that I just read the database are over there.
Ok.
And, that's it now I can compromise...
...can make...again.
So, I can projects.
And, brokering.
Switch so you can see.
A...opening the last document one.
And, create and uone.
I'm going to create a blank documents when I go to my in...you
will see that we have audience here and you will see that because I loaded...
app or adding it's already there I can inserted
This may be americorps issue.
There we go okay so there's something going on so now if
...insert sample data I can see the app that I just
published washer so in a matter of minutes I can really do my
multi devise development really easily so this is one of the
key aspects of the model now let's switch gears and I want to show
you also some of the new capabilities from platform perspective as well as some of
a api what can you do with the api us?
Samoa.
Thanks again all right so let's close...here.
for these next them all we said it's all about productivity so let's
...really enhances the pro tutti of users from scratch so we're going to
them all that allows me to very easily create a project
information in...with nys visualizations so.
In this case let me start a run your project here.
So, I'm going to start and let's call it this is my team.
Builder.
So, I'm going to make it a task...in this case I...focus on the word.
So, all this...of the projects a little bit about this in our in this case
ourselves...person and I all the time so software
projects and most of the time we put the same type of...team structure we have our
...designer we have couple of engineers on a project
lead the only thing that changes is the actual people that are assigned to
a project on the raising the prices so but I want to do this all the time and
it's been a lot of time just reading these diagrams where I pudding work when...the proposals
...so let's see how I can are create a productivity boost
...in a matter of minutes soI'm going to start with the
blind project so let's just are run into see what it does...so the whole project template
from visual studio gives you something that you may be already familiar with
...simple...that allows you to read the selection and display it
on a pop-up now that's not very useful so let's see what
can we do to make it more useful so I'm going to go back to visual studio.
And, open some of the cool behind these the first thing I
want to talk about is one very powerful api
that we have in word that I'm not sure the people realize how powerfully
so I'm going to focus my solution on that one api which is the ability to read and
write open-xml from the document so in this case instead of just reading the
text I'm going to reeves the open-xml
representation of the selection what I do the
...by changing the type that
...request the data out to be return to me in this case I'm doing
...get selected data function requesting text I'm going to change
that to request open xml whoops.
I...these variable to hold the
...so because open some of these much more larger I'm just going to
common these notification...instead of showing it there I'm going to.
Basically put it on that variable so...the xml and...also
...a textbook so that we can see it so for that I'm going to also a
...here...my the fold.
Html so let's see ...those to the apps with you switch back to
word so ok now I have a...works.
Now I have the ability to select something
and get the open-xml representation of that instead of the text
ok that's still not very useful let's make it more interesting so I'm going
...close word and show you are quick trick.
In visual studio if you add
...existing document...one open word.
If I come to the project and rightly can say
...existing items you can select any word document...you have in your machine and
added to your project in this case I have these word document that I want to
uses a template and then just delve visual studio...creating a new document
...five just use the documents I'm going to do that because
that document has the project template I want to automate
now another thing I want to do is I not only want to read the selection I
...to actually...create
...with a xml so let's create a bottom here whoops.
It's create a new
...on that allows me to also set the data.
And, I'm going to go to javascript here and also
...the bottom as you can see m using jake...
So, just need to...the bottom to these said data function so all I need to do is
add the said data function.
...the said data function is
actually really simple as well you can see were only calling the
...selected data api and we're processing that open-xml that we saved
into variable so very simple code so let's see how this looks like.
So, now I open my template document you can see there is the template
that I normally generate also user now I'm going to
our my app team builder...developing it going to
save the document and now the our of open-xml is that you
can not only grab takes you can grab any complex representation of continued words,
for example, in this case I one these diagram this is the type of diagram that I...my opt to generate automatically
for my users sigrid these project simply diagram you can see I have
...holders forwarded data would be...I...this up to do is basically
generate these diagrams dynamically based on data coming from the back so let's see how we can do
that the first thing is this object these are...object I actually spent like a good
...just deciding...looks right so the our of these is that you can
select here.
This whole thing and say get the
data I have now the eczema representation here but now with the said they'd
...the same thing from...works.
Order variable into the document ok so now we have the
ability to anything that I can representing worked I can podium
...template and spit it out now.
Great we just implemented copy...so still not a very useful
what the part of will make it really compelling is if I can replace these...holders
...actual data and make these really dynamic so let's see how we can go and enable
that for this project so for...
I'm going to go back to visual studio and...data models...load...
From some other place in this case I'm going to just...that but I also want to
demonstrate how you can use any of the libraries that are out there
and javascript in this case I'm going to use angular to enhance this
project so angular makes it really easy to...to the down the uri and that's what
I'm going to do so I'm going to include the angular reference there I'm
going to replace these text in the.
Html with some.
Angular definitions for a couple of things I'm going to have a title I have
an angular app and the corresponding
comptroller for those familiar with angular and then I have an imports for the
number of hours...people will be working on and then...for crumble
...to capture...different roles was going to play those roles and a running total
...I can see...who's working on that now that I have that on my html all
I need to do is come back to my javascript and
...the corresponding data model for...in this case I'm going to reach out to a
...for simplicity what you can imagine you could connect to anything...like http,
for example, as we saw in the other case this case I just have some hard
...data...some people and the rates
...angular controller and I'm going to who crop...with the
html may also have some variables for this selected people
...as well as the total number of hours capture from the input
...and a function is going to calculate the total based on what I
selector the only thing that I need is a function that allows me to replace the
...holders with the data the user specifying through the html so I'm
going to go and do that I'm going to insert dysfunction called
assign team which is a very simple function is going to receive template
...in this case and do a
bunch of replacements just string replacements very simple looking for this string
lead and replace it with the actual selected lead from the user okay and then the
last thing is instead of just passing the role...to my
...data I'm just going to before dab pass
it through the replacement functions so I'm going to?
Call assign team here.
...open-xml and the result of that already replaced is going to
be what I want to insert so let's see how about works now
okay so that's going back herereload my
app to get the changes now I'm going to select these again?
Whoops.
The...I'm going to get it and I'm going to inserted.
...with my said the...so you can see now
I have the diagram...with the real data now if I want
to change that I can of course say all this is too much money let'sfind someone else
those in charge of march those reduce the price groups reduce the price
on that one and I want to so, the data again all so
really seems like it reloaded for some reason moi.
Let me go open selects these worm this is a template.
There you go so good from selection on a of the xml and I want to
...these one with...new values...
worries notes and everything okay there you go so now let's select
...one...the reduce
...the price so very powerful now the only thing I don't want the user to be selecting the
template because that's the point right the user...already have...template so let's just
...template as part of my project so the users can use all these
without having to know what the templates so I'm going to our.
Delete these from...file.
...even in the original states...it close word and go
back to visual studio what I'm going to add one file here.
The existing file.
...simple text file.
That basically all it has is that same xml.
I can open that I showed in the textbooks I basically just copied from the...works putting
...put it as part of my...and
...my template so now the only thing I
...need to do is instead of getting the data from
the selection I'm just going to get the template.
So, that change the name of the bottom here and go to my javascript
and goal to the function that gets the data.
So, this is get data from selection I'm going to replace these and
I'm going to put this code and this code basically just loads the
txt file...to the or some of variables so that said
will pick it up so very simple let's see it should work.
Right there's the...now I should be able to come to the end of the document in this
case without selecting anything get the
...ki guarded from the web and then the change some.
People here and then said the data...you
...so now I have a nab that allows me to automatically generate...and we
...just in a few minutes now
this up works rate on the desktop where I have...that support but what I
...these users may not have...the...me want to use word online so let's
publish these two are word online so for that I'm going to.
Use the publishing we start again so bear with me
...these so I'm going to the same thing aidid create
...your profile here.
And, basically deploy this project to...or.
In this case I'm going to select...for inside here.
My them...site and, I'm going to.
Published these or https.
So, this is going to deploy this project that we just creative
...washer now the only thing I need for these to work on the word online
...to now load that manifest into my word online ten
...the same concept that I...for the
...silo the money first so again here is the page so.
Let's see if it's their.
Their releases obviously it's not doing anything because it's
not connected to office but the simple data model is working now let's get the manifest for
...this is the publishing location it's correct
...finish and that gives me the
...for...now all I need to do is come hereand,
navigate to the up catalogue of my...ten and that I'm going to
use...give axis to my users to this up so I'm
going-to drag the money first here.
Okay, so, it's...and now I'm going to...two-one
grieve for business and let's say now I'm a salespersonI've already
obtain these because my idea...input into the catalog I'm going to create a new
projects I have my project template here...arming work online.
I'm going to say...not edit these documenting work online.
So, here's my project template you can see there's a bunch of work I need to do
but when it's time to the team structure I can say hey I want to use
...to create the team structure section of this document
...is...this was just published today to productions so you can now goal
...your tenants and
...new bottom I apps that will allow you to get access to the
option the tenant you can see the app is still not showing there...need to
...and here release-time
builder is the one that I just of loaded I'm going to insert my team to the...adj.
My expectation is that these will do the same thing right so let's probe it I'm going to click the
get template...retrieved the template from the web and now I
want also leg my team configuration that's a that's go with that and...
data and realize...doesn't even support smart I'm
going to insert a chunk of content the user cannot editing word online itself
but the app cam because the app has the our of open-xml so we...I
can insert is diagram in word online and save the user a bunch of time
so this is what I call boosting the productivity of the user...and adding.
...which...to the presentation ok so.
I'll show you a few of the capabilities that we just-releasedso,
let's...just a quick summary of what are all the things that have happened in the last three
to six months so we saw the simplified
getting started experience for those people that want to learn more we saw the...so for which are about
to release in the next couple of weeks we so...word online and
the whole into an experience of developing...something usefulwe are announcing also
a simplified offices...version experience of or for those of you already working with the
...today we have a...scheme that uses to numbers and...was crossing like every time we
...the...more number even though we're not introducing breaking changes you will need to
...to the new version so, the your up
keeps with the latest changes so in order to reduce the friction and simplify these
were going to just go with one version number and, basically not make
raking changes until we change that...so now you can reference the javascript
...of one-point-one you...say one and you will get all the latest
...these we have having to modify your...every time.
Now there's a few things that are ...performance improvements have been
of rolled out a as well as adding for the outlook...you probably so about
them all in the session of the developer kickoff social.
The last
ten minutes I want spends talking about the roadmap what's coming
...in the future.
you also probably so, these...someone's going to spend a lot of time here just one
message we are actively working
on enabling these to all the platforms one of the highest priority
...for my team right now is to make sure that are these are available
and working all the platforms were office works so in the next
three to six months you should expect to see the orange cells coming up
and we're going to talk all the rest...first as...so
ones we're done with the orange we will go after the greening
deal caller now ...one big priority a
secondly priority is deeper integration so this is something that's coming a
...in the user voice so,
you're not already participating in the user voice please do
so we look at it and we understand a lot of the things that people
...to do by looking at the user voice and we have
sharedvery loudly the people
want to deeper integration both in terms of the api so we're going to
...outing and lighting up new deeper api...we're going to start focusing
on word...and we're going to switch from?
The common api that we have today which work...seamlessly
...and powerpoint to deeper specific
api that are specific to word excel so that you can have
phi and grain control over the new functionality that we
will have available and you will of course will be able to use of
...api along...of the new application-specific api
is the target scenarios...we have four word
...document...scenario so basically you everything you need to create these document
assembly scenarios to...reach functionality for your
end-users in xcel there's obviously the data import a analyses and
visualization scenarios that we want to enable a giving access,
for example, to the charts object model which is something that people have requested a lot I want to create and
...that optimizes generation...chart okay
we'll be able to do something like that now the next thing in deeper integration
is the ux so rubble efforts already mentioned
that we're starting to integrate allow you to extend the reborn
we don't see it really one extensibility necessarily we...more
...this notion of adding, adding commands swore
common extensibility the idea is that...will be able to surface comments
...users are already familiar to use those commands so-if is a
reborn is going to be the reborn but there's going to be a layer of abstraction of your
app will declare...you want to show we will
interpret the differently depending on the client so there are...that don't have a reborn
...for example, are the web axis but you will still be able to project commands and
we will make sure that we put them in the right place that makes sense for the user?
So, if you are interested in learning more about these there's a
decision on wednesday four thirty.
Three thirty pm so we are releasing adding comments in outlook
first...we're starting to work on adding...for word excel and powerpoint and,
expect to have those soon the other thing that we're doing is we're also going to enable different add-in
types so you have seen the task being the content
...the case of...we have the reading...and now the new
pop-pop shape that allows you to have contextuallinks.
We're going to starting enhancing the number and the types of
audis that you can create like for some...you want to extend the open
and save experience we maybe able to give you access to the file open
save and led you project some...functionality over...so,
we are still prioritizing what are the first scenario so again user voice will be
a great way to learn about what is important to you bob this is
a another interesting area where we will be investing in the near future and lastly
...to make sure that you have from a developer perspective all the resources
that you need in order to create high-quality jobs that really helps users
...be more productive so we're going to start investing
...things like ...template this is something that has been
requested quite a bit and let me show you just a quick.
Blooms ofsome of thinking on that area.
So, I'm going to open.
This up so the idea here is hot what can we do to help you
to create great looking apps...really fill in fifth-grade in the
society offers uri so we have heard a lot of requests for
like styling guidance and some help to
...do a better job in terms of integrating into the office you
...the office philosophies so we're starting to think about these idea of the office
...fabric or a set of ui templates that you can use to style your you
...app if you will...that it looks and feels better inside of his
are going to have...this case I creative or someone emerging creative these are or
...wvu basically illustrates a lot of the things that
we'll be putting out there are resource for developers you will have access to
...the same phones that we use inside office so, the user can
see the consistency between your app on the office user experience so the icon
...griffey is also very important so we will put icons of the you can use them your
...the users will...cycles branding I goes as well as a function I
goes there will be definition for the callers that offers uses
sort of uone you can match the high logical or...
called or things like that we will also thinking about templates for different things like,
for example, bottoms?
Toggle bottoms different types of choices we also have things like
...you want to create a least in this case we will give you all this
styling that you need to create something that looks and feels like office and the
nice thing about these approach and I would love to hear your feedback of these either
via user voice or you can richard to me directly I can give you
...contact information...decision is are we are
plotting to these in a way that we think is going to be
...to consume so in this case the way you will integrate
...is just by creating some links to some siosism javascript files in your
project that's it and then a series of classes that you need to add
...html elements to basically style them the way office
...the same the same items and then this
is really powerful because it really allows you to basically use the look and feel
but still use any framework image javascript framework
you can use or you want to use for rendering and creating the controls of the
ui you can still use so just to demonstrate that let me show you.
In this case the arby's using angular to...so you can see how
a I can use both these ui fabric and...layer on top of some other
existing framework jake...angular or bootstrap or whatever
framework you're using it still compatible is not going to collide so,
we want-to make sure you can still leverage any of the frameworks...there
...the web so in this case, for example,
if I inserter table here I'm using angular to do some data mining here so I can,
for example, the...something in these table those...like...
beyond your lawry's doing the data binding so, it's very easy to who crop.
And, you can see how the inventing and everything is just being taken care with the office
...to the presentation.
So, hopefully these will be an exciting way to our creed the
ui for.
For your robs we talked about the developer preview programs so
please sign up...you can go to the both and sign up and then there's some subscriptions
...get for free the to get controls from cleric and
...services allows you to...to
...campaigns to follow-up with your contacts so those are great benefits of besides the fact that you
will be able to be in touch with...and give us feedback about the work that we're doing.
So, with that I just...wrap-up with call-to-action so I have to call to
auctionsone is a specific to this session.
Learn more the verbo-visual combs large getting started look,
at the new page there's a lot of simplified
...information but also lots of samples new samples
...testing your audience in word online you can do about to the
...to production these morning so you can just go and
...without also test or start this thing on the x so for.
We released the new version of the manifest
...one-point-one which is the one...you to jump into the.
And, we talk about the new versioning for
...we also release the one version number instead of two please provide those
...warc on user voice.
Develop programs.
There are tones of thoughts...where we will be drilling down into other topics.
And, then the speakers you want to get to...cool who the.
That...now I just means one more them
also I'm out of time but if you guys want to stay I just want to show you are
...of previews of the work that we're doing in
...powerpoint I have botch in my...but so if you
guys have a couple more minutes I can show you that quickly.
Is...make sure that we went over the
Okay, there we go so now.
One of the things I want to show is...that...that we create the project
...in builder of course it...on the so let's see however, worse here.
So, I'm going to open a project template here...
And, I had already
...loaded the manifest for but up here used in builder.
...my as you would expect the object...
In this case already have one
there what I'm going to insert a new one of the end of the document so
let's come here and then get the templates.
It's loaded now I can...as you would...
The reduce now I can also create these experience on the as we
start to enable this type of scenarios disease some of the
new work as you can see were getting really close to a place where we will be able to
...these...we're not ready yet but it's pretty close
we're also starting to work with some of our partners like a...your sign which already polish
...rap and it's already working for the desktop now we're testing
...with the art but so let me go and show you how from here I can also launch
...you sign which is available
there?
And, I can ...the up.
With very almost normally education from the
...your sign guys I have the ob working on the
...I can say I'm done with this project and from within my...but I can say I want to
sign this project now this is going to use the same implementation that they
have that it's working on the desktop that it's also going to work on
word online here on the so it's reading the file it's going to send...to the
...loaded here...I can complete dissing...their...
I can see there's my diagram I
want to put my signature right there so let's
...signature one-inchthe...
...and with that I can just...finish.
The document is now...so I created
a projects with nys diagram that contains information from by
bark and a nice signed it and send it to my client
all from my within a matter of seconds so thank you very much this is
it if you want tofollow-up these...and I can give you a...information thank you.